A Guide to the Mary Baker Eddy Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7589-a
Mary Baker Eddy Collection 1907-1930
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7589-a
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer, 1996 June 21
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Georgine Milmine Welles, Auburn, New York, to R. H. Lyman, Editor of The World, New York, 1909 Dec 7; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Expresses her appreciation for the review of her biography about Mary Baker Eddy which appeared in last Sunday's World.]
  - Georgine Milmine Welles, Auburn, New York, to R. H. Lyman, Editor of The World, New York, 1909 Dec 13; TLS, 2 p. w/env
    [States that the criticism of her biography of Eddy by Mr. Slaght at the end of his article in
    The World
    was valid as "the later events in C[hristian] S[cience] history do need more thorough treatment than I have given them." The remainder of the letter explains why she did not go into greater detail on some of the more recent aspects of Christian Science and her plans for a later edition.]
- Photographs and Engravings
  - Engraving of Mary Baker Eddy by Jules Maurice Gaspard, 1908; Engraving
  - Postcard Photograph of the Christian Science Publishing House, Boston, Massachusetts, 1908 Nov 25; Photograph
- Printed Material
  - "Blamed for his Child's Death Christian Science Father Censured by Jury", 1907 May 18; Clipping (photocopy)
  - "Mrs. Eddy's Life History Told by Miss Milmine [Welles]" review of biography discussed in the letters above, 1909 Dec 5; Clipping (photocopy)
  - "Asa Gilbert Eddy, Christian Scientist - His Ancestry and His Career" in The Christian Science Monitor, 1916 Feb 17; Clipping (photocopy)
  - "Mrs. Eddy Article is Called Biased" in New York Times, 1930 Feb 18; Clipping (photocopy)